Clarence H. Thompson Papers
Clarence H. Thompson Papers
1965-1973
Thompson, Clarence H.
1 linear ft.
Clarence H. Thompson was director of the Evening Liberal Arts Program, Assistant Dean of University College and Dean of University College at Northwestern University. He served on the board of the Association of University Evening Colleges, and was its president from 1969 to 1970. He also served as the President of the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations. Collection contains correspondence and other material concerning the Association of University Evening Colleges, the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations, and the Missouri Valley Adult Education Association
148704
Biographical History
Clarence H. Thompson has been successively Director of the Evening Liberal Arts program, Assistant Dean of University College, and, since 1972, Dean of University College, Northwestern University. IIe has served on the board of the Association of University Evening Colleges, and was its President from 1969 to 1970. IIe has also served as the President of the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The two boxes of his papers date from 1965 to 1973. They concern the Association of University Evening Colleges' regional and national affairs from 1966 to 1972; the Coalition of Adult Education Organizations' from 1971 to 1973; the Missouri Valley Adult Education Association's from 1967 to 1973; and Thompson's own writings between 1963 and 1973.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Most closely related are the following:
Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC)
Coalition of Adult Education Organizations
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Thompson, Clarence H.; Association of University Evening Colleges (U.S.); Coalition of Adult Education Organizations.; Missouri Valley Adult Education Association.; Adult education -- United States.; Educators -- United States.; Evening and continuation schools -- United States.; Correspondence.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC)
  - Annual Convention, Des Moines, 1971-1972; correspondence and printed material (Box 1)
  - Committees, 1970; correspondence (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee, 1970; correspondence (Box 1)
  - Montreal Meeting, Nov 1970; correspondence and printed material (Box 2)
  - Region X, 1966-1970; correspondence and printed material (Box 2)
- Coalition of Adult Education Organizations (CAEO)
  - Correspondence and printed material, 1971-1973 (Box 2)
- Missouri Valley Adult Education Association
  - Correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 2)
- Writings
  - Various, 1965-1973 (Box 2)